Curriculum Vitae – Martin Bjeldbak Madsen

Personal Information Martin Bjeldbak Madsen Born June 9th, 1992 (22 years old) Lærkeparken 20 6230 Rødekro Denmark Mobile: +45 26 27 36 60 martinbmadsen@gmail.com martinbmadsen.dk

linkedin.com/in/martinbmadsen



I was born and raised in Denmark until I was 5 years of age, whereafter we moved for a total of 9 years abroad, 4 of which were spent in England, and 5 in the US. That means that I'm quite used to speaking Danish and English with locals and can adapt to new cultural environments. Currently I live by myself and in the future, I see myself working in the tech, medicinal, or automotive industries.

Currently I'm taking the first year of my masters degree abroad at the University of California, San Diego from Aalborg University here in Denmark. I attend 7th semester and engage in interesting problem-based project group work along with following courses. As an example, we as a 6-man group designed and implemented a programming language from the bottom up to make it easier for non-programmers to design board games.

EDUCATION

I have quite a normal educational background, except for the physical locations! Educational-wise, I plan to take the first year of my 2-year master's in the US and then finish it at Aalborg University.

Aalborg University - Master of Science, Computer Science (2014 - 2016) Working on a master's degree in Computer Science, where the first year will be done abroad.

University of California, San Diego - Computer Science (2014 - 2015) Taking graduate level courses in Computer Science for the first year of my master's degree from Aalborg University.

Aalborg University - Bachelor of Science, Computer Sience (2011 - 2014) Bachelor's degree in Computer Science (180 ECTS credits). I graduated with an average of B on the European ECTS scale.

 $EUC\ Nord$ - HTX (2008 - 2011) Technical gymnasium in Hjørring, Denmark. I took the highest level Math, Physics, English, Electronics, and Danish possible.

Bagterpskolen (2006 - 2008) Completed the Danish Folkeskole Education in Hjørring, Denmark.

J. R. Gerrits Middle School (2003 - 2006) Elementary and Middle School i Kimberly, Wisconsin, USA.

Professional experience

September 2012 → now Student programmer at Falck Healthcare a/s. I develop and maintain a web portal used by Falck's physiotherapists when journaling their contact with patients. I spend around 15 hours per week working there alongside my studies.

Sept 2010 \rightarrow January 2014 Ran my own company, *Divambu*. I developed and hosted web sites for small companies.

October 2008 → June 2010 Service worker at Fakta a/s (part of Coop Denmark). Was in direct contact with customers and fulfilled everyday tasks required to run a busy grocery store. I worked during evenings, weekends, and holidays alongside attending school full-time while I was under 18.

OTHER ACTIVITY

July 2012 → March 2014 Mentor, Project Solskinsunge 2012. Volenteer work, where we arrange bi-monthly social gatherings for teenagers aged 15 – 18, most of which are second generation immigrants.

I've had a Danish driver's license for 4 years.

SKILLS

I can quickly involve myself in new material, but there are a few technologies and systems I have more experience with than others:

Operating systems Basic understanding of most Unix-like systems: Ubuntu, Debian, CentOS, Arch Linux, Mac OS X.

Servers and databases Nginx.

CMS-systems I've set up systems with Wordpress, phpBB, Octopress.

Revision control Git, SVN.

Programming, scripting, and markup languages Land XaleX, HTML, CSS, C, C\psi, Java, JavaScript and jQuery, Ruby and Ruby on Rails.

Language

My native language is Danish, but almost everything I write and read is in English, both academically at university and merely communicating to others when I'm at home, coding or not.

Danish first language Spoken English fluent Written English fluent

Interests

When I'm not in front of my computer, I love to enjoy a cup of tea and read non-fiction. There is also nothing better than travelling the world, so I try to do that as much as possible, and thankfully due to my fantastic friends, I've had quite a few fantastic experiences travelling to visit then. I also enjoy electronic and classical music, such as house and Tchaikovsky. Keeping my body healthy and in shape is also important to me, so naturally I quite enjoy cooking sexy, irresistable food!